

ABOUT ME

Software engineer with 8+ years of experience developing full-stack web services, apis, and websites for digital maps and navigation to help people explore the world. Coding is my craft and I plan to create more products users love. I'm passionate about learning new skills, being productive, and mentoring with care.

CONTACT

LOCATION
Woodinville, WA

PHONE **757-561-8238**

EMAIL

msnider.software.engineer@gmail.com

WEBSITE msnider.com

MICHAEL SNIDER

Senior Software Engineer

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Microsoft

Aug 2016 – Present (8 years, 9 months)
Directions (2022 – Present). **Route enrichments** for maps, bing, and copilot working across multiple stacks. **Modernization** of bing route apis

with .NET Core on Linux and gRPC for azure route apis. Polyline smoothness. 1% drop in bad requests. **Delayed segments** for mobile. Route debugger website. Commute ETA lookup on windows.

Beacon (2016 – 2021). **Device location** notification service for teams, family safety, bing, and outlook time to leave. Batch inference infrastructure. Location inference viewer website. **Home/work** apis.

Hackathon achievements. **Bring my pet home collar** (2019 One Week, 2nd place in Maps and Geospatial), Find my family (2017 Cortana Skills, 1st place), and Music ticket bot (2017 One Week, 2nd place Millennials).

Software Engineer Intern, Microsoft, Open Roads

2013 - 2015 (3 summers)

Microsoft (2015). **Location history** for Microsoft privacy dashboard. **Speed test** search result for Bing (hackathon).

Open Roads Consulting (2013, 2014). Event planning, travel time, and localization for the **traffic management system**. Website for quality assurance.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science, University of Virginia

Aug 2012 - May 2016

3.941 GPA; Capstone map website for the Rivanna Trails Foundation; Undergraduate Thesis on societal values in online privacy.

Google UX Design Certificate, Coursera

Mar 2023 - Sep 2023

7-part course with 3 projects with hands-on experience with research, wireframes, mockups, prototypes, and usability testing.

SKILLS

Languages

C#, TypeScript, Python, Java, CSS, HTML

Frameworks

ASP.NET Core, gRPC, Node.js, React, Vue.js

Software

Git, VS Code, Azure, CI/CD, K8s, Copilot, Figma